<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Theo&#x27;s blog</title>
    <link href="https://blog.theocraft.tech/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://blog.theocraft.tech" />
    <updated>2019-01-29T22:08:16+08:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Theo</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://blog.theocraft.tech</id>

    <entry>
        <title>RareBirds 1st 2019 PH Summit - Day 1</title>
        <author>
            <name>Theo</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blog.theocraft.tech/rarebirds-1st-2019-ph-summit-day-1/"/>
        <id>https://blog.theocraft.tech/rarebirds-1st-2019-ph-summit-day-1/</id>
            <category term="tech"/>
            <category term="summit"/>
            <category term="start-up"/>
            <category term="events"/>

        <updated>2019-01-29T12:05:06+08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blog.theocraft.tech/media/posts/2/Image-from-iOS-1.jpg" alt="Rarebirds Philippine Team" />
                    Hi! the PH RareBirds team is having it's first PH summit this year today, which is dedicated to push growth and bind the team more closely. RareBirds btw, is an awesome start-up company based in Sydney, Australia that has an awesome offshore team here in PH that&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://blog.theocraft.tech/media/posts/2/Image-from-iOS-1.jpg" alt="Rarebirds Philippine Team" />
                <p><strong>Hi! the PH RareBirds team is having it's first PH summit this year today, which is dedicated to push growth and bind the team more closely.</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://rarebirdslabs.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">RareBirds</a> btw, is an awesome start-up company based in Sydney, Australia that has an awesome offshore team here in PH that works remotely. And a few times a year, the entire PH team meets up, mostly somewhere near the capital to do events that we call <strong>Summits.</strong></p>
<p>We are doing these summits to experience working &amp; collaborating with the team face-to-face, after a few months of chatting &amp; staring at each other through the screen. </p>
<p>The venue for this event is <strong>Sharvd Coworking Space</strong>, Makati Philippines which has a nice place to collaborate. We thank Mel for booking the place, and the RareBirds management for supporting the event! </p>
<h2 id="mcetoc_1d298v8o41">Day one</h2>
<p>Almost everyone from the Rarebirds PH team have gathered here in makati to be part of the event. The early part of the day have mostly been travelling! But most of us have arrived on the venue early which is awesome.</p>
<h5 id="mcetoc_1d299m5di3">Here is the list of activities we have in line for the day</h5>
<ul>
<li>Catching-up! (Story telling, listening to weird laughs, making the mood light)</li>
<li>360 Degree Evaluations</li>
<li>Presentation of the organizational chart</li>
<li>Sprint Retrospective(Discussion of the good, the bad &amp; the nice things)</li>
<li>Visa Application (We're flying to Australia soon!)</li>
</ul>
<h5 id="mcetoc_1d29a0npq4">Catching-up while doing 360 degree evaluations!</h5>
<h5 id="mcetoc_1d29989la2"><img class="post__image" src="https://blog.theocraft.tech/media/posts/2/day-1.jpg" alt="" width="4000" height="3000"></h5>
<p>This is almost all of the dev team! They are busy multi-tasking (evaluating &amp; story-telling) </p>
<h5 id="mcetoc_1d29n00480"><strong>Lunch break!</strong></h5>
<p>One of the tough(answering the endless question "What to eat") yet exciting part of the day, the <strong>lunch break</strong>!</p>
<p><img class="post__image" src="https://blog.theocraft.tech/media/posts/2/IMG_20190128_125337.jpg" alt="" width="3000" height="4000"></p>
<p>We were fortunate to be treated to one of the best restaurants near Sharvd - and this is our talikogenic(beautiful back in tagalog slang) dev, Seus! </p>
<p><img class="post__image" src="https://blog.theocraft.tech/media/posts/2/Image-from-iOS-2.jpg" alt="" width="4032" height="3024"></p>
<p>The team is starving and eager to eat, but still looks happy and energized!</p>
<p><img class="post__image" src="https://blog.theocraft.tech/media/posts/2/food.jpg" alt="" width="3000" height="4000"></p>
<p id="mcetoc_1d29on6m41">Ha! Thank God, the wait is over. Seus(blue on left) was so happy, he can now eat beef! after being alergic with it for a long time. </p>
<h5 id="mcetoc_1d2bdtj660">Presentation of an organizational Chart</h5>
<p>RareBirds is a start-up, which started having a flat(anyone talks to everyone) organization. And after a couple of sprints, have decided to have some level of order. The dev team looks excited, having to see a clearer view as to <strong>who takes ownership of what</strong>. </p>
<h5 id="mcetoc_1d29oklm40">Sprint Retrospective</h5>
<p>The TYM team just finished its sprint last friday, so it's time to look back &amp; asses how things have turned out, discuss the good, the bad and the nice things. Lots of improvement points have laid out(which is good) and most of them are dedicated to setting a <strong>better</strong> <strong>experience </strong>for the team. </p>
<p>Since the retrospective had some long and nice discussions plus the team is super flexible, we had decided to move the visa application to the next day. </p>
<p>This concludes the first day. It was mostly warming up for the 2nd day and catching up face-to-face with the team which is really helpful when folks are working from home, wearing their pajamas or shorts.<br><br>I will be posting an update for the 2nd day. Stay tuned!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
